









Ishita Kabra



Skills

Architectures

GraphQL, REST, MVC

Languages

Javascript, Python, HTML, CSS, Golang, Java

Frameworks & Tools

ReactJS, NodeJS, Selenium, OpenCV, Docker, Nginx

Cloud

AWS, Heroku, GCP

Databases

MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL

Other

Markdown. Git, PWA, Figma, Adobe PS, Adobe Al

Technologies

Electronics, Micro-controllers, IoT, Image Processing, DSA, DBMS

Interpersonal

Mentoring, Problem solving, Communication, Teamwork, Decision making, Dependability

Education

B.Tech - ECE - IoT

Electronics & Communication (Spl. IoT) Vellore Institute of Technology - Vellore. CGPA: 8.95

Languages

Hindi, English

References

Codebugged Al

+91 8004006979 Mr. Sarthak Srivastava

Umbrette

+91 8920380318 Mr. Manoj

HEED India

+91 9820305933 Mr. Jignesh Barasra

About

Ishita is a full-stack developer & a 3rd year student at VIT Vellore, pursuing B. Tech in Electronics and Communication (Spl. IoT). She has 1 year of experience with web based tools & technologies. With her knowledge of IoT & love for development she builds secure and creative web experiences.

Full stack developer & 3rd Year Undergraduate

Work Experience

MERN Stack Trainer - Codebugged AI

March 2021 - May 2021

Formulated a course and and hands-on projects for a 2-month MERN training.

React.is, Node.is, React Context, MongoDB, Git, REST, MVC, API Security

Software Developer Intern - Umbrette 2

Nov 2020 - April 2021

Built a full-stack solution for a freelance marketplace for job seekers and employers.

React.js, GraphQL, MySQL, Node.js, Websockets, oAuth2.0

Software Developer Intern - Codebugged AI

Aug 2020 - Nov 2021

Developed a full stack solution for employ and resource management for Oil India Civil department ReactJS | NodeJS | MongoDB | express | Cloud | React Native

Project Lead - HEED India 12

March 2021 - May 2021

Led a team of developers to build a website and a content management system for an NGO React. is, REST, MongoDB, Node. is, Role based Authorization, PDF Generation, Handling media files

Projects

QuiCLI - A CLI based deployment tool [2]

Deploy on VM |Dockerization of repos | Auto DNS Configuration | PORT management | CI/CD | Rollback to last stable release

ResuME - Auto-generate website using data from LinkedIn 다

This project is under development | Selenium | Node.js | Python fire | Bash | Git | Docker

Chat.io - One-One chat application ☐

Real time | E2E Encryption (in progress) | Online and last seen status | Notification alerts | Request alerts

MediumRare - A Blog Application ☐

Golang | Recommendation System | oAuth 2.0 | Elastic Search | Project is in final stage of development

Typeface - Rich text editor NPM Package for react ☐

Lightweight | React.js | NPM

AtishiBoT - A discord chat bot and more [2]

Moderator features | Music Player | Chat Bot | Google search | Stack overflow search | Web Scraping

Achievements

- · 1st Runner Up At Devsoc'21 Hackathon Codechef VIT
- · Qualified For Nationals At Microsoft Imagine Cup 2020
- · Projects Lead At The Electronics Club VIT
- Member Of The Organizing Committee Of GraVITas, The Annual Technical Festival At VIT.
- · Coordinator At Parallax 2019, A Hackathon By TEC VIT
- · Speaker At A Technical Workshop, Sensored 5.0, 2019

Certifications

· AWS IoT: Developing And Deploying An Internet Of Things - Coursera, Offered By AWS